A Guide to the Harry M. Miller papers FA742
Rockefeller Archive Center
Harry M. Miller papers
1936-1972
Rockefeller Archive Center
Miller, Harry M.
Rockefeller Foundation
FA742
1.13 Cubic Feet 2 legal document boxes and 1 half-letter box.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Papers were donated to the Rockefeller Foundation by Harry M. Miller, Jr. in 1967.
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Harry Milton Miller Jr. (1895-1980) served the Natural Sciences Division of the Rockefeller Foundation as a fellowship administrator (1932-1934), assistant director (1934-1946), and associate director (1946-1950).
Arrangement
Arranged into two series: 1. Correspondence. 2. Publications.
Scope and Contents
Primarily contains correspondence.
- Correspondence, 1936-1972; 1; 0.66 Cubic Feet 1 legal document box and 1 half-letter document box
  - A, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - B, 1936-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - C, 1950-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - D, 1964-1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - E, 1961-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Fund for Overseas Research Grants and Education (FORGE), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - F, 1961-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - F, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - G, 1959-1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - H, 1961-1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - J, 1960-1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - K, 1961-1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - L, 1960-1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - M, 1959-1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - N, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - O, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - P, 1960-1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - R, 1959-1970 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - S, 1964-1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - T, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - V, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - W, 1962-1971 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Y, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Publications, 1951-1962; 2; 0.47 Cubic Feet 1 legal document box
  - Reports, Photo, Articles, 1956-1962 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes a photograph of "Paris Exposition, 1937, George W. Bakeman, Dr. Wilbur E. Tisdale, Robert Letort, Harry M. Miller Jr., and Thomas B. Appelget".
  - Pamphlets, 1951-1961 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - "Atas do Primeiro Simposio Sul-Americano de Genetica, Presidente de honra e homenageado Dr. Harry M. Miller Jr., Sao Paulo 8 a 11 de Marco de 1960", 1961 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - "Botanica 17, Boletim da Faculdade de Filosofia, Ciencias e Letras, Universidade de Sao Paulo, en homenagem a Harry M. Miller Jr. (1960)" and "Anais da I Reuniao Brasileiera de Genetica Humana, Buritiba (1959)"., 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - "Hommage to Dr. Harry M. Miller Jr., members of the Department of Biology, Instituto de Biologia 'Jun Noe', Universidad de Chile", 1960 (Box 3, Folder 28)